# Edwin Detrez Jr | Full Stack Software Engineer

(407) 616-1222 | edetrezjr@gmail.com | Orlando, FL

linkedin.com/in/edetrezir/ | github.com/edetrezir | www.edwindetrez.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Motivated Full Stack Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience in software development. Proficient in a variety of programming languages and frameworks in addition to Agile development methodologies. Strong creative problem-solving skills, communication skills, and programming expertise. Currently teaching over 40 student software engineers full stack development using JavaScript, React, Express, NodeJS, and PostgreSQL.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

<u>Proficient</u>: JavaScript, NodeJS, Express, React/Redux, React Hooks, Git, Github, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Axios, AJAX, Webpack, Firebase / Firestore, Material UI, Agile Methodologies

Knowledgeable: System Design, AWS, Python, MySQL, JWT, OAuth, Bootstrap, Heroku

Familiar: Java, React360, GraphQL, Socket.io, Babel, Mocha, Chai, MongoDB

#### **PROJECTS**

<dotGuide /> | Software Developer | https://readme-c72e5.web.app/

A developer tool for storing reference code, creating educational guides, and standardizing best practices with code.

- Completed full stack (front-end + backend) slices for a user's ability to create and view guides
- Built authentication backend in firebase and connected it to the frontend signup, login, and profile components
- Created search feature which allows user to find a guide from the homepage using keywords

Tech Stack: Firebase / Firestore, React, Javascript, Node.js, Material UI, and Codemirror

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Academy | Full Stack Software Engineering Mentor | New York, NY | 4/2022—Present

- Teach JavaScript, React, Redux, Hooks, Express, NodeJS, PostgreSQL, Agile Methodologies, Axios, AJAX, object-oriented programming concepts, and more to 40+ student software engineers
- Support underrepresented students in tech with Future Code's values of Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion
- Debug and problem-solve students' code while guiding students to the intended solution
- Leverage instructional resources, proficient knowledge of programming, and computer science principles to meet the needs of students with varying backgrounds and experience

United States Air Force | Cybersecurity Flight Commander | Vandenberg AFB, CA | 06/2018-04/2019

- Spearheaded \$3.5M Top-Secret training facility project to train over 1,100 Airmen per year, by developing innovative training software, implementing modern technology such as AR/VR, and building program interfaces
- Modernized training materials for Space/Missile Operators by facilitating transition from paper materials to encrypted iPads in \$300k effort
- Personally mentored 200+ Airmen in leadership training, career progression, and technical skills training
- Negotiated fiscal contracts for innovative technology, software, and developmental materials for the Air Force.

## Addition Financial | Department Administrator | Lake Mary, FL, | 06/2016-06/2018

- Generated data-driven analytical reports by querying SQL databases to project business needs and goals
- Transformed a low-ranked regional department to become a top-producing revenue-generator yielding more than \$40k per month in interest from loans, a record 48% increase over the previous year

### **EDUCATION**